Guide to the Ipas Records, 1965-2020; 1965-ongoing RL.00617
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Policy Unit, 1991-2010; 16 boxes
  - Policy Unit 97-98: world abortion laws 97; conscientious objection 97; Namibia 97; Russia 97; AWID roundtable 97; new ideas 97; Partners in Pop and Dev first mtg 97; FIGO Manila 97; Romania 97-98; MLP supporting statements/docs 97-00; FIGO 97-00; FIGO 200 misc 97-00; RH background 97-03; MLP background 97-05; India 98; Mongolia 98; Algeria 98; Barbados 98; Bulgaria 98; Ghana 98; LSS Module 10 PAC 98; AB Care Manual south Africa 98; Safe Motherhood materials 98; Partners in Pop and Dev 3rd board mtg 98; Partners in Pop and Dev general 98-01; midwives and Ipas 98-02 (Box 172)
  - Policy Unit 99: Partners in Pop and Dev 4th mtg 99; legal reform background 99; violence against women 99; AWID panel and papers 99; midwives/ICM donor proposal 99; ICM Manila planning and reports 99; ICM surveys 99; ICM Manila papers 99; ICM Baca & Huapaya talks 99; resources for ICPD+5 Issues 99; Safe Motherhood White ribbon Alliance 99-01; Uganda 99-01; ICM trip reports 99-02; Kenya 99-04; Asia 99-06; Nigeria 99-05 (Box 173)
  - Policy Unit 00-02: Ipas and ICM policy overview 00; Indonesia 00; child rights/UNICEF 00; ACNM mtg 00; Garate consultant 00; sexual violence presentation 00; WHO Midwife module Kenya field test 00; WHO midwives 00; Midwives for Choice 00-02; FIGO 2000 and FLASOB 00-01; FIGO 2000 panel 00-01; Ipas MLP task force 00-02; USA 00-02; Peru 00-02; India 00-05; LA policy 00-06; Ethiopia 00-06; FIGO 2000 Ethics survey 01; FIGO ethics statements 01; FIGO 2000 booth 01; FIGO survey responses 01; FIGO 2000 LA panel 01; FIGO 2000 FIGO 2000 Africa panel 01; ACNM abstracts 01; ICM Zimbabwe mtg 01; ICM journal Oguttu PAC article 01; ICM Ipas papers and presentations 01; ICM "making a difference" Amakhosi play 01; Quito partners conf 01; T&L 01-02; FLASOG CDSR 01-03; Global Gag Rule 01-03; Evals/3rd World Network 02; WHO/MLP Della 02; Bolivia violence 02; Africa Alliance 02; advocacy concept piece 02; IJGO article FIGO surveys 02; policy assessment 02; WHO 02; ACNM 02; MLP bibliography 02; MLP country reports 02; MLP conf remarks 02; ICM 02; FIGO CWSRR mtg 02; D Billings Mexico MLP trip reports 02 (Box 174)
  - Policy Unit: 02-03: AMRN mtg/Arusha 02; policy unit overview 02; PAC eval Bolivia 02; El Salvador 02; cmite DSR 02; Pop Council PAC mtg and Mex team 02; rights background 02; Rebecca cook 02; Mexico 02; unsafe abortion in Africa background 02; Catholics for Free choice 02; Mexico City policy article 02; US MLP paper 02; RH background 02; MA 02-03; Peru PAC trainers proposal 02-03; Dr. Ortiz corresp 02-03; US program 02-03; policy unit docs 02-03; policy retreat 02-03; policy unit mtgs 02-03; Safe Motherhood initiative 02-03; Adolescent Working Group 02-03; Central America 02-03; Anibal Faundes work/contract 02-04; AWID 02-04; Pop Council quality 02-06; MLP Issues dissemination 02-08; FLASOG 03; FLASOC panels 03; FLASOG workshop 03; FLASOG papers 03; GEM 03; Ipas LAC mtg/training 03; sexual violence on-line resources 03; Amanitare conf 03; WHO Safe AB mtg 03; HIV 03; Addis communique 03; Inter-European Parl Forum on Pop and Dev 03; Women's Global Network of RR 03; DeBruyn pubs 03; AIDS 2002 conf 03; health conditions abortion 03; GTZ presentation 03; returned FIGO surveys 03; ectopic El Salvador 03; Uruguay legal reform 03; Romania 03; Caso Rosa 03; Peru 03; NCWU Women's Advocacy Day 03; CFC 03; MLP mtgs 03; US advocacy planning 03; CTL policy mtg 03; planning objectives 03; MLP Brazil 03; EC 03; technical unit forum 03; Ramatu Nigeria 03; Aspire 03; rights and reform 03; London FIGO CWSRR mtg 03; ECSR 03-04; cost model 03-05; UN/DAW 03-06 (Box 175)
  - Policy Unit 04-05: WGNRR 04; CRR-global AB policy presentation 04; ECSAOGS workshop report 04; Ipas lessons learned 04; APCRSH Bangkok 04; adolescents and abortion laws 04; FIGO SRR/D Shaw 04; MA Task Force 04; FIGO 2003 04; FIGO 2003 panel presentations 04; FIGO 2003 Ipas reception 04; FIGO panel speakers invitations 04; Sofigo 04; Africa/feminist perspective paper 04; CEDAW mtg 04; ACOG/AB policy article 04; Hord article rape/abortion 04; LAC pretest WHO slides 04; Morocco 04; speakers bureau – Oguttu 05; Ipas messaging 04-05; opposition 04-05; adolescent RH 04-05; Ayotte case 05; Alliance Circle of Friends workshop 05; US abortion map 05; ICPD+10 roundtable 05; World Social Forum Brazil 05; Advocacy & networks presentation 05; DFID/AGI presentation 05; Uganda 05; Brazil 05; Bolivia 05; policy retreat 05; SisterSong 05; Europe trip report 05; Countdown 2015 AB working group binder 05; Oguttu visit 05; LAC advocacy 05; CD mtg 05; misc policy notes 05-06; IPPF annual reports 05-06 (Box 176)
  - Policy Unit 06-10: women with HIV/AIDS 06; human rights 06; ICM 2005 06; Board strategic visioning – adolescents 06; GHC 06; lobbying presentations 06; Uruguay presentation 06; IWHM 06; Southern Girls Convention 06; ICM 06; MENA region 06; Advocacy workshop 06; Cambodia 06-08; Med Students for Choice 07; youth 07; FIGO 07; Namibia 07; Peru 07-08; ICW 07-09; Mexico AB arguments 08; ICM 08; Alliance policy logframe 09; Ipas press release 09; policy workshop Cambodia midwives 09; India 09; AIDS conference 2008 09; AB litigation reform Southern Africa mtg 09; newspaper article SRR Nigeria 09; SRR pre-congress workshop FLASOG 09; de Bruyn workshops 09; Africa policy retreat 10; policy retreat Nica 10; Beijing + 15 10; NGO ltr to Clinton 10; women and AIDS background 10 (Box 177)
  - Policy 89-12: Brazil abortion paper 89; ICPD+5 99; women and media 99; pubs requests 99-05; men as partners 01-10; Addis mtg paper 03; ICPD+10 04; monitoring tool MOUs 05; unit retreat 06; Caribbean safe abortion mtg 06; Athena 06-08; HIV/abortion presentation 07; GOS TOT development 08; religion/abortion; women HIV/AIDS 08-09; FIGO 09; M&E tool Namibia workshop 09; Namibia monthly repot 09; Malawi evals and surveys 09; Malawi reports 09-10; FEMNET report 10; unit retreat 10; MA in Ghana paper 10; Malawi 10-11; Malawi trip 11; Keeping Our Promise conf 11; notes mtg B Crane 11; Africa Conf on SRHR 12, 1989-2012 (Box 234)
- Health Systems Research (HSR)/Research & Evaluation (R&E), 1987-2011; 9 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  - Health Systems Research: 1987-1993 Background info USSR and Eastern Europe 87-92; Romania corresp 90-93; Pop Council seminar 91; Mexico 91; World Bank cost study 91; WHO – Romania 91; Romania donor report 91-92; Romania donor corresp 91-93; Romania 91-92; questionnaires 91-97; papers/misc 92; Zimbabwe 92; women's perspectives presentation to board 92; Romania field reports 92-93; Romania reports/pubs/background 92-93; Romania notes 92-93; Am Anthropology Assoc paper 92-93; cost study to SS&M journal 92-93; notes/workplans 92-93; Ghana corresp 92-95; Zimbabwe PAFP research/corresp 92-96; workshop agendas 93; Eval framework 93; World Bank cost study paper 93; GIRE contracts 93; interview training 93; Lancet submission 93; Guide to Assessing Resource Use for the Treatment of Incomplete Abortion 93; Zimbabwe 93; Romania 93; APHA Romania paper 93; MVA summary Mexico 93; GIRE corresp 93-94; Verkuyl – Zimbabwe 93-96; Tanzania workshop corres 93-95; Zimbabwe PAFP operations research corresp 93-96; articles 93-96; Ipas-authored articles 93-02 (Box 132)
  - Health Systems Research 1994-1995 Background Eastern Europe abortion 94; Psychosocial workshop 94; HHRAA questionnaire 94; HHRAA lit search 94; Zimbabwe national conference corresp 94; Zimbabwe national conference materials 94; Zimbabwe 94; Romania medical abortion 94-95; Lancet commentary 94-95; Janie Benson talks 94-97; Colombia meeting 95; Tanzania OR corresp 95; Tanzania workshop 95; HHRAA monograph 95-96; Chile 95; Ghana data analysis 95; INOPAL contract 95; Safe Motherhood slides 95; Vietnam trip report 95; LAC abortion researchers mtg 95; Zimbabwe OR proposal 95; Vietnam background 95; Vietnam evaluation materials 95; Vietnam corresp and reports 95-96; Vietnam 95-98 (Box 133)
  - Health Systems Research 1996-1998 Zimbabwe master questionnaire 96; Zim research permit 96; Zim summary data 96; Zim project 96; Zim PAFP OR proposal 96; Zim PAFP TOT 96; Zim site data 96; Zim OR 96; South Africa 96; HHRAA monograph dissemination 96; SSA article 96; Mexico Abortion opinions paper 96; Egypt PAC study 96; HSR presentation of projects 96; Kenya OR questionnaire 96; Ronnie Johnson 96; trip reports 96; Peru INOPAL 96; Africa OR proposals 96-97; data collection instruments 96-97; INOPAL cost manual 96-97; Zim 96-98; Janie Benson 96-00; Kenya OR paper 97; Ipas values scan 97; INOPAL 1st report 97; IMSS women's eval 97; Background Ethiopia RH assessment 97; Nica PAC/MVA paper 97; women's perceptions abortion 97; Rebecca Cook program 97-98; INOPAL 97-99; DataPAC paper and presentation 98; Peru PAC study reports and presentation; 98; Pop Council PAC OR conference 98; Ghana midwives study MotherCare 98; APHA 98; library eval resources 98; "against the current" article 98; MotherCare matters newsletter 98; qualitative life histories 98 (two files) (Box 134)
  - Health Systems Research 1998-1999 WHO Romania study 98; WHO proposal 98-99; Client Perspectives on Quality of Contraceptive and Abortion Services at Three Sites in Vietnam 98; Background South Africa 98-01; Refugees 98-03; DATAPAC Core Questionnaire Series for Postabortion Care Operations Research 99; Serie de cuestionarios centrales de DataPAC para la investigacion operative sobre la atencion postaborto 99; Kosovo refugees 99; PRIME presentation at ACNM 99; Nica 99; training 99; Columbia RH seminar 99; Cuba 99; HSR planning and pubs 99; Ideas – PAC OR projects 99; Egypt Frontiers 99; Ghana 99; Studies in FP article 99; India PRIME and AAP 99; Frontiers position 99; OR meeting 99; quarterly HSR review 99; Frontiers description /proposal 99; Ipas role in Frontiers 99; Peru ideas & corresp 99; Hurricane Mitch 99; South Africa TOP mtg 99; Ethiopia report 00; M&E strategy 99; CPC Inst on M&C 99; M&E background 99; Policy and eval 99; South Africa 99; marketing & eval 99; PRIME M&E eval 99; Frontiers working files: proposal 99-01, financial reports 99-01; Bolivia subagreement 99-01; reports 99-01; comms others 99-01; background 99; trip reports 99-01; U.S. early abortion study 99-00; HSR unit management 99-03 (Box 135)
  - HSR/R&E 2000-2002 Trip report Romania WHO 00; Poland background 00; South Africa Midwives AB report 00; MA services APHA presentation 00; Janie Benson Peru dissertation 00; evaluation indicators 00; Peru PAC sustainability proposal 00-01; IRB ethical review 00-01; model project 00-03; R&E Nigeria 00-04; Mife/miso 00-04; MA background 01; Peru workshop 01; Peru data collection proposal 01; Eval Ethiopia and Nigeria 01; R&E retreat 01; Ethiopia 01-02; Zimbabwe 01-03; TeenWeb donor proposal 01; TeenWeb IT 01; TeenWeb website design 01; TeenWeb IRB 01-02; TeenWeb pilot testing assent forms 01-02; TeenWeb Nairobi schools 02; TeenWeb other youth questionnaires 02; TeenWeb MOUs 02; TeenWeb internet in Kenya news articles 02; TeenWeb modules shown to schools 02; MVA course eval Brazil 02; recap Ipas presentations and pubs 02; audit tools 02; Guyana assessment 02; Huapaya presentation PAC/rights 02; WHO Romania assessment 02; ESPS survey results 02; M&E instructions 02; Gen MIS 02; Romania family health initiative 02; Ethiopia 02-03; Kenya 02-03; core indicators 02-03; GEM 02-04; Tanzania 02-04 (Box 136)
  - R&E 2003-2005 Afghan refugees 03; bibliography abortion/fertility transition 03; Bosnia trip report 03; Ipas evaluation 03; Thailand facility assessment 03; overview of R&E 03; Vietnam CAC OR proposal 03; health sector reform 03; Measuring Ipas impact 03; PAC Peru survey presentation 03; staff vision survey 03; Mongolia 03; FP for factory workers background 03; Onyango paper ECSAOGS 03; Vietnam monitoring 03-04; background HIV/RH 03-08; Monitoring US/Europe/Asia region and general 03-06; Monitoring Africa region and alliance 03-06; R&E Bangladesh 03-08; Stanley Henshaw 04; DC march 04; Liz Asia mtgs 04; feminist perspective Africa paper 04; Powerpoints/presentations 04; sexual violence working paper 04; trip report VN staff 04; ethical review process 04; CAC research Vietnam 04; DFID 04-05; R&E pubs Ipas 04-05; WHO Eastern Europe and Russia assessments 04-05; ethical reviews 04-07; IDEAS (International Data for Eval of Abortion Services) 05; WHO Romania factory study 05; conscientious objection 05; rights-based approaches to health care 05; outcomes/cost estimates unsafe abortion paper 05; Mozambique study 05; completeness study protocol Mozambique and Cuba 05; M&E 05-06; savings survey 05-07 (Box 137)
  - R&E 2006-2009 Africa Consortium Conference 06, Africa research conference talks 06; MVA distribution data and analysis; planning and review 06; scaling up resources 06; Advocacy task force 06; El Salvador 06; abortion and RH indicators 06; Cambodia 06-08; proposed R&E activities Ethiopia 07; PAHO machine translation system training 07; expanded M&E 07-08; R&E publications 07 (notebook); COMPAC tool 07 (notebook); TSDI/R&E mtg 07 (notebook); R&E mtg 08 (notebook); TSDI/R&E 08; safe abortion care Ethiopia 08; sexual violence surivivors 08; Ethiopia OE report 08; Ipas MVA SWOT 08; abortion reform Impact on MM 08; Ghana 08; Africa Abortion Research Consortium 08-09; R&E unit management 08-09; IRB LAC studies 08-09; Project management workshop evals 09; R&E planning 09; Ethiopia 2nd trimester study 09; questionnaires 09; monitoring indicators 09; SAC Tigray 09; World Bank M&E proposal 09; MDG modeling 09; Ipas impact 09 (Box 138)
  - Health Systems Research / Research & Evaluation 90-04: J Benson trip report to Mex 90; Bellagio press release 93; Zim OR proposal 95; Kenya OR proposal 95; Peru – Carrion – memos to field 97-98; Peru – Carrion – papers/presentations 98; INOPAL Peru baseline report 98; studies Carrion manuscript 99; Pop Council comms 99; Zim PAFP study presentation 99; PAFP transparencies 99; project dev Peru study 99-00; Kenya 00; staff workshop PAFP lessons learned 00; eval work 00-03; Peru trip reports 01; Peru qualitative 01; Peru sustainability project reports 01-02; R&E retreat 02; Exec team 02; Peru PAC survey 02; Peru PAC mtg 02; US study article 03; Peru paper 03; 4 country scale-up study 04; World Bank cost study 04; RUWDUC Nepal 04; APHA Peru PAC talk 04; eval 04-05, 1990-2004, 1990-2002 (Box 202)
  - Health Systems Research / Research & Evaluation 05-11: Binkley talk 05; R. Johnson 05; HPME-Bolivia 06; Cost of abortion M&M mtg 06; cost effectiveness measures 09; Zambia mife 09-10; staff retreat 10; Zambia MA study 10; contracts/consulting 10; Medabon docs 10; Zambia MA study - data collectors training 10; Zambia MA study – comms survey training 10; GEM training and reports 10; RA1 – M&E 10; M&E for CDs 10; UNC – IRB 10; clinical trainees M&E 10; Results internal newsletter 10; logframes 10; IUSSP paper – SAF Ethiopia 10; M&E planning 11; WHO – MA & Nepal 11; Ghana/Zambia stigma protocol 11; GEM M&E packet 11; M&E data tools ppt 11; Costs PAC Malawi report 11; Nigeria planning 11; GEM data 11-12, 2005-2011 (Box 203)